Diogo Freire

Product, Project and Program specialist from Papamoa, Aotearoa New Zealand +64 21 140 1055 | me@diogofreire.com | linkedin.com/in/diogofreire

SUMMARY

I'm a project and product lead with a development background and experience leading projects and building productive communication across multiple teams and business units. I have a passion and specialise in Fittech/Healthtec and have delivered several projects in my career that benefit the business and deliver value and impact for their customers. I pride myself on my positive and supportive leadership style. I also have mean drumming abilities and pick up heavy objects and put them back down for fun.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bank of New Zealand, Senior Project Manager [contract] — June 2024 to Present

- Short-term contract to create processes to facilitate delivery items that required multi-team coordination in the Core Ledger Replacement initiative.
- Established a set of Non-functional Requirements and a process for attesting them within the project, which has been adopted bank-wide.
- Created processes to document and operationalise high-risk items such as review of Tech Specs and Batch Operations and lead work to ensure security policies and practices were well followed within the project.

PushPress, Product Manager (Core) [fully remote] — June 2022 to June 2024

- Gym Management software used by 3,000 gyms worldwide managing 200k members
- I manage the main B2B2C product for the company and am responsible for billing, user management, lead
 creation pages and platform services used by other products. I also have led several squads across the
 company, focusing on building relationships and processes for collaboration with leads across the
 company.
- I delivered projects that supported market expansion (international payment methods, complex plan setups), supported large tech-debt projects (booking system revamp) and increased early-day activation (new client sign-up and member migration workflows).
- I implemented a new reports system that replaced and consolidated data points and reduced bug
 reporting by 80% while delivering insights for clients that helped them optimise operations efficiency and
 costs.
- Improved signed-up conversion by 40% via a new workflow.

CarbManager, Product & Growth Director and Product Strategist [fully remote] — May 2021 to Jun 2022

- Lead nutrition app in the Keto and low-carb space, with 12 million downloads worldwide.
- I was responsible for product vision and strategy. I've delivered projects that increased competitive advantage and conversion (intermittent fasting, integration with fitness trackers) and projects that streamlined main tasks for users (food logging, food validation workflow).
- I led and mentored the product team on discovery and validation practices and increasing cross-functional capability across the company. We delivered several projects that increased user retention and early-day engagement.
- I managed the marketing team and coordinated efforts between product releases and marketing campaigns to maximise impact for users and business. I delivered projects that increased the conversion

to paid users from marketing nurture campaigns by 7%.

Alphero, Innovation Manager (Ideas Factory Manager) — Apr 2019 to Sep 2020

- I led the innovation programme, reported to the CEO, and was responsible for researching and summarising broader market trends and internal ideation processes and establishing constraints and directions for prototyping work.
- I created a strategy for bringing an innovation framework to clients, helped them work on steps to develop a culture of innovation and facilitated time-boxed projects with their teams.
- I've worked with large clients such as Tempo NZ (Fintech), Auckland City Council and NZ Customs to ideate and implement initiatives to solve complex challenges for those organisations.

DNA Design, Development team lead — Jul 2018 to Apr 2019

- I managed a group of 13-15 developers across multiple cities and supported and mentored the Project Management team.
- I engaged with the broader business to improve processes and project outcomes, strengthen client relationships and help refine the engagement model for ongoing contracts.
- I also acted as Scrum Master across several teams and projects and led hiring and performance review processes with team members.

Alphero, Project Manager — Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

- I worked on delivering web, app (Apple and Android ecosystems), and backend projects with budgets ranging from \$ 5k to \$ 2 m.
- I delivered programmes for financial institutions, utility providers, government, media, telco and others with team members distributed across New Zealand.

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Functional Adaptive Movement[™] (FAM), Coach Mar 2021 to Present
- CrossFit 5011, Crossfit, Olympic Weightlifting and Brand X Youth Coach Nov 2018 to Jul 2022
- Self-employed, Personal Trainer May 2020 to May 2021
- Full-time Parent Aug 2017 to Jul 2018
- NV Interactive, Project Manager Mar 2014 to Jul 2015
- Ushahidi, Project Manager (Remote Contract) Feb 2014 to Mar 2014
- Self-employed, Project Manager / Developer Aug 2013 to Feb 2014
- Touchcast, Senior Developer Mar 2013 to Aug 2013
- Springload, Project / Account Manager May 2012 to Jan 2013
- Springload, Senior Developer Dec 2008 to May 2012
- Hollo Interactive, Lead Developer Mar 2004 to Aug 2008
- Dominio Sistemas, Support Analyst Jan 2000 to Aug 2002

SKILLS AND TOOLS

- **Product management**: Jira, Contentful, UserTesting
- Project Management: Trello, Harvest, Xero, Google App Script, Linear, Notion, Google Docs Suite
- Analytics and insights: Google Analytics, Redshift, Amplitude, Looker, QuickSight, Mode, Segment
- Sales, Marketing and CX: Hubspot, Intercom, LeanPlum, Apple and Google Store Ad Management
- Financial Integration: Stripe, Google and Apple Pay, FastSpring
- Technical Stack Experience: AWS, Flutter, React, PHP, GraphQL, ML/AI, NodeJS, Google Cloud,

RudderStack, Vue.js, Firebase, NodeJS, Identity management, Java, Swift, Algolia, Accedo, Silverstripe

- Testing and QA: TestRail, Cucumber + Gherkin, BrowserStack, Mobot
- Innovation technologies: Alexa, Android and Apple Auto, Google Glass, Tuya, Unity, VR/AR, D3.js, Siri, Google Assistant, Torch.py, TensorFlow

CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

- Reforge, Product Strategy Nov 2021
- PMI, Project Management Professional (PMP) 2015
- ICAgile, Agile Facilitator (Lyssa Adkins and Michael Spayd) 2013
- Scrum.org, Professional Scrum Master I (PSM1) 2013
- Zend, Certified Engineer in PHP 2011

EDUCATION

- Victoria University of Wellington, Masters in Information Management 2012 [Incomplete]
- New Zealand School of Music, Foundation Certificate in Jazz (Drums) 2011
- UniBH, Bachelor of Telecommunications Engineering 2008
- CEFET-MG, Diploma in Industrial Computer Science 2004

LANGUAGES

Fluent English and Portuguese, fluent in Spanish reading and slowly improving at listening and speaking.

VOLUNTEER WORK

- Torch, Professional and Career Mentor Mar 2022 Present
- Wellington Regional Emergency Management Office, Crisis Mapping Technology Advisor 2010 to 2016
- Ushahidi, Developer 2013 to 2016
- Wellington Zoo, Audience/Logistics 2014 to 2016